The next few topics will cover unit testing
and how unit testing is done in Python.
Before we cover unit tests, we need to define
unit testing.
Unit testing is testing done on a small unit
of code, usually to check the functionality
of that code.
For example, we can use a unit test to test
logic within a game, such as whether two values
that should be equal are equal.
Running a unit test involves adding code we
need to become familiar with.
I will go through this code, the 531-unittest
file, from top to bottom.
First, we need to import the unittest library
to have access to the built-in unittest functions.
That code is on line 1.
Unittests are inside classes.
On line three, we have a class that I named
TestMain that holds a test case as an argument.
Within the class, a function is defined.
The function needs to start with the word,
test.
I named this test test_location as a unit
test for colored locations in a game.
The self argument indicates a self-contained
unittest.
I have two values assigned to variables a
and b on line 7 in this test.
The real test is on line 8.
This assertEqual test is one of many assertion
tests we can run.
We will cover assert methods in more detail
in an upcoming video.
The assertEqual test asserts whether two values
are equal.
The code on line 10 is an if statement indicating
that, if we are in the app's main file, to
run the unittest.
I will run this code, and we get a failure,
as the two values are not equal.
I will change the b variable to red and run
this code again.
This time, the test succeeds, as a = b.
Unit tests are important because they provide
an effective way to test a small amount of
code, and in doing so, one can more easily
isolate potential problems within an app,
pinpoint where those problems are, and fix
them.